Good news, everyone.
We've got a very special delivery today.
- Who's it going to?
- Me.
Another job well done.
No, I need it shipped to my office
at Mars University.
It's a little experiment
that may well win me the Nobel Prize.
In what field?
I don't care. They all pay the same.
- Is it dangerous?
- Oh, my, no.
Off we go.
Very impressive.
Back in the 20th century, we had no idea
there was a university on Mars.
Well, in those days,
Mars was just a dreary,
uninhabitable wasteland, much like Utah.
But unlike Utah,
it was eventually made livable
when the university was founded in 2636.
They planted traditional college foliage,
ivy, trees, hemp.
Soon, the whole planet was terra-formed.
Does that mean
it's safe to breathe the air?
Of course.
Over here is Wong Library.
It has the largest collection
of literature in the western universe.
Hey, look. There's a chapter
of my old robot fraternity.
Epsilon rho rho.
You went to college?
Of course. I'm a bender.
I went to bending college.
I majored in bending.
- What was your minor?
- Robo-American studies.
Are you here to fumigate the moose head?
Uh, no. Actually,
I'm an epsilon from way back.
Eh. Close enough. Come on in.
Thanks. Here's your finger back.
All the coolest robots
are in this fraternity.
Mate in 143 moves.
Poo. You win again.
Oh! Nerds.
Allow me to introduce myself.
I'm Gearshift, chapter president.
This is Oily, and this here is Fat-Bot.
You're all losers. My name's Bender.
Bender from Bending State Bender?
Wow! You're a legend around here.
I heard that in one single night,
you drank a whole keg,
streaked across campus
and crammed 58 humans into a phone booth.
Yeah, well, a lot of them were children.
Anyway, I should get going.
No, Bender, wait.
We're the lamest frat on campus.
Even Hillel has better parties than us.
Please, you've got to stay
and teach us how to be cool.
Mmm.
Okay, but I'll need 10 kegs of beer,
a continuous tape of Louie Louie
and a regulation
two-story, panty-raid ladder.
Oh, boy, oh, boy, oh, boy.
I tell you, being here
really takes me back
to my college days.
Step right up. Who wants to learn physics?
Keep your hands
inside the car at all times.
Good old Coney Island College.
Go, whitefish!
Don't take this the wrong way, Fry,
but you don't seem
- like the educated type.
- Oh, yeah? Read it and weep.
I'm a certified college dropout.
Please. Everyone knows
20th century colleges
were basically expensive day care centers.
That's true.
By current academic standards,
you're merely a high school dropout.
What? That's not fair.
I deserve the same respect
any other college dropout gets.
By God, I'm going to enroll here
at Mars University
and drop out all over again.
You won't last two weeks.
Ah! Thanks for believing in me.
Yo, classmate, whatcha taking?
Oh, I don't know.
Professor, what are you
teaching this semester?
Same thing I teach every semester.
The mathematics
of quantum neutrino fields.
I made up the title
so that no student would dare take it.
"Mathematics of wonton burrito meals."
I'll be there.
Please, Fry. I don't know how to teach.
I'm a professor.
See you in class.
This is gonna be great.
- Bingo.
- Oh, Mama.
Oh, yeah. Someone's been a bad computer.
Get a load of that.
I say, you've damaged
our servants quarters
and our servants.
This time, Robot House has gone too far.
Cheese it!
Hey, pretty nice for a single.
Two desks, two chairs, a couple of beds...
A woodpecker.
I think that's probably your roommate.
Right, cool. Come on in, roomie.
Huh?
- What the...
- I call top bunk.
Ah!
- My roommate's a monkey?
- Brilliant deduction.
You're a credit to your species.
Ah, Fry. I see you've met Guenter.
You know each other?
Guenter is my experiment.
He was the top-secret contents
of this stinking crate.
I'd rather live in a crate
than share a room with this dork.
- So, what makes Guenter talk?
- Is he genetically engineered?
Oh, please. That's preposterous
science fiction mumbo jumbo.
Guenter's intelligence actually lies
in his electronium hat
which harnesses the power of sunspots
to produce cognitive radiation.
You're wasting your breath, Professor.
he'll never understand a word of it.
I understood the word "hat."
Please, stop bickering.
I arranged that you be roommates
for a reason...
So I'd only have to remember
one phone number.
Now shake hands and make up.
You want a banana?
I don't eat bananas.
I prefer banana-flavored
energy bars made from tofu.
I don't like you.
This is gonna be a cake walk.
Welcome to the history
of the 20th century.
Look to your left, then to your right.
Then in nine other directions.
One of the 12 of you
will not pass this class.
Boring. Let's hear about
Walter Mondale already.
Be forewarned. The only sure way
to get an A in this class
is to have lived in the 20th century.
Swish.
You were saying, Mr. Fry?
I'm from the 20th century.
Go ahead. Ask me anything.
Very well. What device invented
in the 20th century
allowed people to view broadcast programs
in their own homes?
Oh! I know this.
What do you call it? Lite-Brite.
I believe the answer is the television.
Very good, Mr. Guenter.
Wow. Smart and cute.
What I love about being dean of students
is the peace and quiet
and the respect I receive.
Now, what's all this about?
Dean Vernon, the students
from Robot House are here.
Robot House.
Hey, Dean. Nice looking model.
You keep away from it.
You robots are a disgrace
to this university.
Whenever a fire alarm is pulled,
it's Robot House.
Whenever the campus liquor store
is looted, Robot House.
Whenever a human corpse is desecrated...
Now, I can explain that.
That's enough out of you.
From this day forth,
Robot House is on dodeca-tuple
secret probation.
- No fair.
- My mom is gonna kill me.
Now, if you'll excuse me,
I have to get back to the one
thing that's kept me sane
these past eight years, my model ship.
Fat-Bot, no!
When I get nervous, I get hungry.
Cheese it!
Robot House!
So, Chrissy,
we seem to be hitting it off.
If you're not doing anything later,
might I escort you to a kegger?
Not even if you were the last man on Mars.
Hey, you like bananas?
I got her number.
How do you like them bananas?
And therefore, by process of elimination,
the electron must taste like grape-ade.
Sorry. I overslept.
Until 5:00 p.m.?
It's that obnoxious monkey.
He kept me up all night
with his constant thinking.
Just thinking and thinking.
He's trying to make me look like an idiot.
Don't be jealous. Without his special hat,
Guenter might be no more
intelligent than you.
I hate that rodent.
Fry, that monkey
is my most important experiment.
If you two don't stop fighting,
I'll have you both neutered.
That'll show him.
Dean Vernon, I'd like you
to meet my parents, Leo and Inez.
Ah! Mr. and Mrs. Wong.
I'm so glad we could admit Amy
in exchange
for your generous contribution.
How much more for phi beta kappa?
How much you got?
Sorry I'm late.
I was off at a study session
with Chrissy.
Oh, I'm glad you made it, Guenter,
because in honor of parents weekend,
I have a special surprise for you.
Mom! Dad! What are you doing here?
This is so humiliating.
Now, these monkeys I like.
What's that? You want to come out?
No! Stop!
I say.
What's that they're flinging at us?
Dear lord. All over the dean.
Hey, why don't you get up
on the chandelier with your parents
and I'll take a picture.
Oh!
Well, looks like
this party's winding down.
Let's take a road trip to Tijuana
and get Fat-Bot some action.
It's my first time. I'm really nervous.
Robot House!
What you did to Guenter was cruel.
At the risk of sounding
like an after-school special,
I think we learned
who the real animal was today.
You mean peer pressure?
Look out. He's got a gun!
Leave me alone.
Hey, what's going on?
I thought you didn't like bananas.
Of course I do.
I try so hard to fit in,
but seeing my parents act like that
made me realize
I'm just a primitive beast.
Hey, hey, cheer up.
Not everyone turns out like their parents.
I mean, look at me.
My folks were honest, hardworking people.
Besides, Guenter,
you're not like other monkeys.
You've got the hat.
So what? I mean, sure,
it looks cool and it makes me smart,
but it doesn't make me happy.
That's so sad.
I didn't even know monkeys could cry.
They can't. It's all the hat.
Look, Guenter,
if you're so miserable here,
maybe you should just
go back to the jungle.
The jungle...
But I couldn't do that to the professor.
I'm his prized experiment.
And he's like a father to me.
But he's not your father.
That guy in the punch bowl
was your father.
Look at him. I'm so proud.
Thanks, Professor.
Not you.
Ow!
Oh! I always feared he might
run off like this.
Why? Why?
Why didn't I break his legs?
Oh, poor Guenter.
So, he just ran away
in the middle of the exam?
I'm afraid so.
All he handed in was a paper
smeared with feces.
He tied with Fry.
I guess he realized I was right
when I told him to go back to the jungle.
You what? After I spent months
slaving over a hot monkey brain?
Hey, don't blame me.
You tried to force Guenter to be a human,
but he's an animal.
He belongs in the wild. Or in the circus
on one of those tiny tricycles.
Now that's entertainment.
But Guenter's obviously
better off being intelligent.
Tell him, Leela.
Uh-uh. I'm staying out of this.
Now, here's my opinion.
What we should do is...
What?
I said we'll go to the jungle
and let Guenter decide once and for all.
What?
You all know the rules.
Whichever house wins the regatta
becomes head of the Greek council.
And should that house
currently be on any type of
multiple secret probation,
it will be lifted
and I will be forced
to serve as grand marshal
of a parade honoring them.
I say, Robot House,
your watercraft is as ill-designed
as you yourselves.
Good one, Chet.
Oh, yeah? Watch this.
Well, I never.
Fraternities, on your marks.
Hey.
Wow, the jungles on Mars
look just like the jungles on Earth.
Jungles on Earth?
I see some movement up there.
I think it's him.
Stand back.
Oops.
Don't worry, they'll be fine
once the tranquilizer wears off.
There's our man.
Professor, you'll offer Guenter the hat,
and, Fry, you'll offer him the banana.
We'll let him choose
whether he wants to be intelligent
or just a mindless animal.
Mmm, mmm.
Come on, Guenter, take the hat.
No, the banana, the banana.
Consider the philosophical
and metaphysical ramifications of the...
Banana, banana, banana.
Wait. What's that sound?
Hey, Bender,
are you sure this is a shortcut?
Not as sure as I was an hour ago.
And the winner is...
Robot House?
Whoa! Whoa! Whoa!
- Oh, no!
- Help!
Thank God this log is sturdy.
Oh!
Put on the hat, Guenter!
You're the only one who can save us!
Stupid monkey.
- No!
- Not there.
Keep trying.
Eureka! The hat goes on the head.
It's all so obvious now.
Help us, Guenter!
Oh, my goodness.
Hang on! I need to do some calculations!
The decimal goes...
Carry the seven... Got it!
Grab on!
- We're saved.
- Appreciate it, Guenter.
Oh, no! Hurry, Guenter. Climb up the vine!
You can still save yourself!
Why bother? I've got nothing to live for.
I was miserable as a genius.
And as a monkey, I was so dumb
I tried to wear a hat on my butt.
There's just no place
for me in this world.
Although, on the other hand...
Oh, that poor, sweet monkey.
Well, let's go gather him up.
There's no sense letting him go to waste.
Guenter, you're alive.
I guess the hat must have broke my fall.
It seems to be working
at only half capacity, but I can fix it.
No, wait! I like it like this.
I actually feel sort of happy.
But what about your super intelligence?
When I had that,
there was too much pressure to use it.
All I want out of life is to be
a monkey of moderate intelligence
who wears a suit.
That's why I've decided to
transfer to business school.
No!
Come on, everyone!
Big party at Robot House!
- You know you make me wanna
-Shout
-Kick my heels up and
-Throw my hands up and
-Shout
-Throw my head back and
Come on, now
Don't forget to say you will
Yeah, yeah, yeah
Say you will
Say that you
Say that you need me